

Mainak Bhowmick

4 Ananda khan lane, P.O – Hath khola, Kolkata, WB, 700005 | 8017818573 | Bunty 6225@gmail.com

Objective

Seeking a challenging position and a satisfying career to utilize my skills and abilities in an organization that offers professional growth on being ingenious, innovative and flexible with a diverse workforce. Articulate and friendly with a professional demeanor that will employ my ability to manage guests, colleagues and maximize the work and the position in the hospitality industry by further exploring my skill sets and bring them to effective use for achieving the organizational and personal goals.

Career Summary

An adept 2+ years hospitality and administration professional with an experience of having worked with 5 Star hotel organizations and fitness industry, and provided the best of professional guest relations and services by maximizing the sales and upselling, in order to provide a recurring business in a pleasant manner and make every guest visit a memorable experience.

Accomplishments

For more than 2+ years, my effective leadership in managing corporate, association and social accounts has produced winning results. My exceptional communication and relationship building has made me develop my guest relationships at all levels and build loyalty with the top guests. By anticipating the guest's needs and going above and beyond their expectations, I have been instrumental in securing repeat business, client retention as well as build brand loyalty. My wide industrial experience across multiple sectors and knowledge has allowed me to meet the organizations', my sales team and my personal and financial goals.

Education

BACHELOR OF HOTEL MANAGEMENT & CATERING TECHNOLOGY $\mid 2013 - 2017 \mid$ maulana abul kalam azad university of technology, west bengal

Skills & Abilities

SERVICE EXCELLENCE

• Genuinely warm presence, friendly, sincere nature, drive for service excellence, internally proud, outwardly gracious and humble, natural ability to anticipate guests' needs.

DETAILED ORIENTED

· Care and attention to details in a multi – tasking environment.

FUNCTIONAL KNOWLEDGE

· Familiarity with 5 star expectations for Front Desk, Reservations and Service Center.

OPERATIONAL COMPETENCE

· Ability to learn and follow the service standards, programs, policies and procedures.

EXCELLENT COMMUNICATION

• Full professional English language proficiency, full professional Hindi language proficiency, along with full Bengali language proficiency.

LEADERSHIP

- · Able to motivate and encourage fellow colleagues to execute tasks in an efficient manner during crisis. Earned a reputation as a valuable and cooperative co worker.
- · Fair, honest and willing to help colleagues and guests when needed.
- · Effectively resolved conflicts at appropriate times.

DECISION MAKING

· Decision Making – Able to prioritize, making prompt and reasonable decisions.

PROBLEM SOLVING

• Adept juggling multiple needs, calmly, respectfully, creatively and successfully resolve problems, as required.

EMOTIONAL MATURITY

· Interact with others in a respectful manner, with demonstrated qualities of sincerity, helpfulness, courtesy and humility.

ETHICAL AND PROFFESSIONAL CONDUCT

• Ethical and Professional Conduct – Fulfill the responsibilities with highest degree of integrity.

TECHNOLOGICAL PROFICIENCY

· Competent in systems used within department, including window based programs.

ATTITUDE AND APPEARANCE

· Hardworking and efficient, with a "never say no" attitude. Neat, professional appearance with an immaculate grooming sense.

RESPECTFUL

- · Enjoy working with people from diverse cultures.
- Exceptional ability to build long lasting relationships with clients and colleagues.

Experience

OFFICIATING FRONT OFFICE EXECUTIVE | MARRIOTT INTERNATIONAL, COURTYARD BY MARRIOT BENGALURU HEBBAL - PREOPENING | Dates From - To

- · As a Front office associate with Marriott International, Courtyard by Marriott Bengaluru Hebbal (Preopening), deliver sophisticated and warmly authentic services in a comfortable and luxurious atmosphere that cultivates fulfilling experiences for both colleagues and guests.
- Responsible to keep this promise by delivering premium choices, sophisticated style, and well-crafted details. With skills and imagination, innovate and reinvent the future of travel for the guests.

SENIOR SALES EXECUTIVE | HAUTE FITNESS | JAN 2017 - OCT 2017

INTERNATIONAL EXPOSURE INTERN | INTERCONTINENTAL HOTELS GROUP (IHG), BERLIN, GERMANY | APR 2016 - APR 2016

INTERNSHIP | MARRIOTT INTERNATIONAL, HYDERABAD | SEP 2015 - MAR 2016

VOCATIONAL INTERNSHIP | TAJ GROUP OF HOTEL (IHCL) | JUNE 2014 - JUNE 2014

Honors & Achievements

PREOPENING CERTIFICATE OF RECOGNITION | FEBRUARY 2018 | MARRIOTT INTERNATIONAL, COURTYARD BY MARRIOTT BENGALURU HEBBAL (PREOPENING)

• Awarded and identified for excellent services in preopening stage to successfully place the hotel and front office department in operations.

CERTIFICATE OF MERIT | MAULANA ABUL KALAM AZAD UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, WEST BENGAL | 2017

· Awarded and honored by certificate of merit for being first and become an all-rounder university topper.

CERTIFICATE OF APPRECIATION - HOUSEKEEPING | MARRIOTT INTERNATIONAL, HYDERABAD | 2016

· Awarded with certificate of appreciation for exemplary performance showcased during internship in housekeeping.

Core Competencies

- · Leadership
- Presentable, outgoing, self confident, and ambitious
- Highly motivated team player with optimistic outlook & attitude.
- · Natural ability in anticipating guests' needs.
- Exceptional ability to build long lasting relationships clients and colleagues.
- Good presentation, communication and interpersonal skills.

- Experience in the similar capacity with a luxury hotel.
- · Natural ability in anticipating guests' needs.
- Strong organizational skills with the ability to multi task.
- Strong work ethic performed in the highest integrity.
- Enthusiastic to the job whilst able to challenge the status quo.

- Excellent knowledge and experience in rooms division's operations.
- · Attention to detail, service mind oriented.
- · A team player, dependent, highly motivated, mature and able to work independently with high speed of execution.

INTERESTS

- Travelling
- · Travel photography
- · Cooking

- · Music
- · Reading

PERSONAL PROFILE

· DATE OF BIRTH: 10th APRIL 1995

· FATHER'S NAME: MR. MANIK LAL BHOWMICK

· **GENDER:** MALE

· MARITAL STATUS: UNMARRIED

DECLARATION

I HEREBY, DECLARE THAT THE ABOVE STATEMENTS MADE BY ME ARE TRUE, COMPLETE AND CORRECT TO The best of my knowledge. I agree that, incase the company at any time finds that the information provided above is not true, correct or incomplete, the company will have the right to terminate my engagement/employement without ant prior notice or compensation at anytime, not withstanding any other terms of engagement/employement.

SIGNATURE: PLACE: Bengaluru, KA, India